Evan Walter

linkedin.com/in/-evanwalter/ • github.com/Evan-Walter • evanwalter.dev

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer specializing in React. With over 10 years of experience delivering technical solutions, I bring real business value in a timely manner. With experience managing technical projects, I leverage leadership skills to serve teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full Stack, React/Redux, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Python, GitHub, REST API, JSON, Firebase, JavaScript Frameworks, JavaScript Libraries, Front End, Back End, PHP, Laravel, Bash, Shell Scripting, Linux, C/C++

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer (Contract)

Sole Proprietorship, Redding, CA

January 2021—Present

- Develop custom solutions with JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3, and Liquid—the Shopify back end theme templating language written in Ruby
- Interface directly with clients to deliver front end web development and Wordpress development
- Manage client websites and assets with Python scripts, applications, and Amazon AWS Cloud API integration
- Optimize website performance by 20% along with git source control, theme kit, and data backups

Full Stack Software Engineer (Contract)

Rewired.one, London, UK (Remote)

September 2021—November 2021

- Implement requested client UI and UX features weekly in well-designed, testable code with full stack React, Node.js, Express, and MySQL
- Build quality, innovative, and fully performing software that complies with coding standards and technical design to execute the full software development life cycle (SDLC)
- Integrate software components into a functional, full stack software system and source control on GitHub
- Develop software testing, verification plans, and quality assurance (QA) procedures
- Report to the project manager and leadership to define personal goals and mentorship

Electrical Designer

Electric Innovations, LLC, Redding, CA

October 2019-January 2021

- Develop highly detailed, custom designs for a broad scope of new and existing systems, saving the company hundreds of hours on system maintenance and troubleshooting
- Deliver on time with tight deadlines

- Align drawings with coding standards and conventions
- Perform job duties that exceed expectations with flexibility, little direction, or direct supervision
- · Communicate effectively with team members and clients as an outward-facing member of the team

Electrical Engineer

Newport News Shipbuilding, Newport News, VA

September 2016-September 2019

- · Create electrical designs for components, equipment, systems, and networks
- Improve key customer products with work package data, SAP programming, Visual Basic code, and Microsoft Excel spreadsheets
- Troubleshoot and test shipboard electrical solutions while working directly with customers

Junior Computer Engineer

ECS Federal, LLC, Arlington, VA

June 2015-March 2016

- Create a testing strategy that the team fully adopted as their new technical workflow
- Design software, firmware, and hardware with VHDL, FPGAs, Xilinx ISE, and Altera/Intel Quartus
- Integrate analog RF systems for low observables from the bottom up, including component level design, plate testing, system integration, and digital control
- Test equipment with technical instrumentation Modulation Analyzers, Oscilloscopes, Spectrum Analyzers, PNAs, Frequency Counters, and Logic Analyzers

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

George Mason University • Fairfax, VA • May 2015

ACTIVITIES

- I am involved with local meetups such as Redding Area Designers and Developers (RADD), Shasta Ruby User Group (SHRUG), and Startup Redding.
- · I teach kids computer programming.
- I enjoy outdoor activities, music, and spending time with family and friends.